<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on mashally</title>
    <link>https://blackaly.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on mashally</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 22:24:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blackaly.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ibn Al-Muqaffa&#39; 32</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/anthology/ibn-muqaffa-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 22:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/anthology/ibn-muqaffa-32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;إن استطعت أن تزل نفسك دون غايتك في كل عليس ومقام ومقال ورأي وفعل فافعل، فإن رفق الناس إياك فوق المنزلة التي تُحطَ إليا نفسك، وتقريبهم إياك في الجلس الذي تباعدت عنه، وتعظيمهم من أمرك ما لم تعظم، وترتيبهم من كلامك ورأيك ما لم ترتبن، هو الجمال.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Third Thought</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/thoughts/third-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/thoughts/third-thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Better to keep a small habit alive than chase a perfect plan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Second Thought</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/thoughts/second-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/thoughts/second-thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If a sentence is unclear, the thought behind it is probably unfinished.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Thought</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/thoughts/first-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/thoughts/first-thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Small ideas are still worth writing down. They keep the day from blurring.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Jargon File</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/books/the-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/books/the-f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Short notes about why this book stuck with me and where it fits in my reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Jargon File</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/books/the-jargon-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/books/the-jargon-file/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Short notes about why this book stuck with me and where it fits in my reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Nature of Reading</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/on-the-nature-of-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/on-the-nature-of-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading is not merely the act of decoding symbols on a page. It is a conversation across time, a meeting of minds separated by centuries yet united in thought.&lt;span class=&#34;sidenote-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;sidenote-ref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sidenote sidenote-right&#34;&gt;1. really?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we read the ancients, we do not simply consume their words. We enter into dialogue with them. We question, we agree, we dispute. The text becomes a living thing, breathing new meaning with each encounter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lost-art-of-slow-reading&#34;&gt;The Lost Art of Slow Reading&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our age has forgotten how to read slowly.&lt;span class=&#34;sidenote-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;sidenote-ref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sidenote sidenote-left&#34;&gt;2. Great&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tradition and Modernity: A False Dichotomy</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/tradition-and-modernity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/tradition-and-modernity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are told that we must choose. Either we embrace the new and cast off the old, or we cling to tradition and reject progress. This is a false choice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wisest cultures have always known how to hold both. They honor what has been proven by time while remaining open to genuine improvement. They distinguish between change for its own sake and change that serves human flourishing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-weight-of-inheritance&#34;&gt;The Weight of Inheritance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To inherit a tradition is to receive a gift and a responsibility. Those who came before us labored to understand the world. They made mistakes, but they also discovered truths. To dismiss their work is arrogance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity in Design</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/simplicity-in-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/simplicity-in-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The pursuit of simplicity is not a retreat from complexity. It is the hard-won result of understanding what is essential and having the courage to remove everything else.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A simple design does not happen by accident. It requires more thought, more refinement, more willingness to discard what does not serve the whole.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-tradition-of-less&#34;&gt;The Tradition of Less&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The great craftsmen understood this. A Shaker chair. A Japanese tea bowl. A Roman arch. Each achieves its beauty not through addition but through restraint.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Reflections</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/morning-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/morning-reflections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The early hours belong to thought. Before the day&amp;rsquo;s demands crowd in, there is space for reflection. The mind, rested and clear, moves freely among ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have made it my habit to rise before dawn. In the quiet darkness, with only a lamp for company, I read and I write. These hours are my own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-routine&#34;&gt;On Routine&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Routine is not the enemy of creativity. It is its foundation. The writer who waits for inspiration will write little. The one who sits down each morning, regardless of mood, will produce a body of work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Note on Correspondence</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/note-on-correspondence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/note-on-correspondence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The art of letter-writing has nearly vanished. Email has made communication instant but has robbed it of weight. We dash off messages without thought, knowing they cost us nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A letter, by contrast, demands effort. The choice of paper, the forming of words by hand, the journey through the post—all these invest the message with significance. The recipient knows that time and care went into its making.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I maintain correspondences with a handful of friends. Our letters are slow, sometimes months apart. But each one is considered. Each one matters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ملاحظات على الشعر</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/arabic-poetry-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/arabic-poetry-note/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;الشعر العربي تقليد عريق يمتد لأكثر من ألف وخمسمائة عام. في قصائده نجد الحكمة والجمال والحقيقة الإنسانية.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;القصيدة الجيدة لا تُقرأ مرة واحدة. تُقرأ وتُعاد قراءتها. في كل مرة نكتشف شيئاً جديداً.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Writing Clearly</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/on-writing-clearly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/on-writing-clearly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Clear writing is clear thinking made visible. When our prose is confused, it is usually because our ideas are confused. The discipline of writing forces us to discover what we actually believe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-enemy-of-clarity&#34;&gt;The Enemy of Clarity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The chief enemy of clear writing is pretension. We reach for impressive words when simple ones would serve. We construct elaborate sentences to hide the thinness of our thought. We mistake obscurity for depth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Defence of Boredom</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/defence-of-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/defence-of-boredom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have declared war on boredom. Every idle moment must be filled. We carry devices that promise infinite entertainment. We have forgotten how to wait, how to be still, how to be alone with our thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a loss greater than we know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-uses-of-emptiness&#34;&gt;The Uses of Emptiness&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Boredom is not mere absence. It is a space in which something can happen. When the mind is not occupied, it wanders. It makes unexpected connections. It surfaces thoughts long submerged.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/thoughts/heelo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/thoughts/heelo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;asdsd&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
