<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on mashally</title>
    <link>https://blackaly.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on mashally</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blackaly.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What happend to people??</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/what-happend-to-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/what-happend-to-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I try to understand what’s happening to people, I’m amazed at why they do this to themselves. I don’t pretend I’m special, and yes, I make mistakes sometimes, and I have to admit I grew up around people who lived simply and within their means which made me think wisly in a lot of things around me. But what I see now is that people are living inside their minds, what is that mean? I mean people, as I see, no longer think about the consequences of what they do or what I am buying today will reflect to my expenses in the future or not, they don’t have a long-term plan for their &lt;strong&gt;financial expenses&lt;/strong&gt;. They only think about the current moment, regardless of whether what they are buying today will affect their future expenses which, in my view, is a red flag for our generation. Our generation is very easy to manipulate and control because of what people see every day on Reels and TikTok videos and you without feeling it or being aware of it, can change your attitude and way of thinking and I wouldn’t be exaggerating if I said your whole personality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Les Fleurs du mal</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/books/les_fleurs_du_mal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/books/les_fleurs_du_mal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Broken Wings</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/anthology/gibran_the_broken_wings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/anthology/gibran_the_broken_wings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;وقد أوجدت الكآبة بين روحي وروح سلمى صلة المشابهة، فكان كلانا يرى في وجه الثاني ما يشعر به قلبه، ويسمع بصوته صدى مخبَّآت صدره، فكأن الآلهة قد جعلت كل واحد منا نصفًا للآخر يلتصق به بالطهر فيصير إنسانًا كاملًا، وينفصل عنه فيشعر بنقص موجع في روحه.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;إن النفس الحزينة المتألمة تجد راحة بانضمامها إلى نفس أخرى تماثلها بالشعور وتشاركها بالإحساس، مثلما يستأنس الغريب بالغريب في أرض بعيدة عن وطنهما، فالقلوب التي تدنيها أوجاع الكآبة بعضها من بعض لا تفرِّقها بهجة الأفراح وبهرجتها. فرابطة الحزن أقوى في النفوس من روابط الغبطة والسرور. والحب الذي تغسله العيون بدموعها يظل طاهرًا وجميلًا وخالدًا.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Third Thought</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/thoughts/leaving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/thoughts/leaving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;كل رحيل يزيل جزء من الإنسان حتى يصير عدماً، ويصبح المرء مجبرا، ولا خيار له، أكثر قسوة. تصبح أكثر وعيا وبالتالي أكثر حذرا وبالتالي أصبحت المواقف والاشياء التي كانت تهز مشاعرك وتحرك قلبك، جامدة، تصبح أكثر تمسكا ووعيا وفهما بمفهوم أن يكون لديك أب وأم وأخوه بعد أن كنت مغيباً، وتصبح أكثر غنى عن من حولك وأكثر وحدة. هذا التغير في الإنسان هو العدم، العدم ثقيل على روح الإنسان، هذه النظرة الثقيلة للحياة على أعين الإنسان تنزل كالصاعقة على نظرة الإنسان لذاته على شيئ ظن انه حقيقة في نفسه، ظن انه كنة ذاته، تنزل لكن بدون صوت أو ضوء، تغير أشتات الإنسان دون أن يشعر، و دون أن يعقلها أحد.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>نظم التشغيل: 1</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/os-ar-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/os-ar-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;مقدمة-عامة-تاريخ&#34;&gt;مقدمة عامة (تاريخ)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;في الشابتر ده، هنتعرف مع بعض على المفاهيم الأساسية اللي لازم تبقى فاهمها قبل ما تخش بجد في عالم الـ Operating Systems. انا هحاول في الـ tutorial دي اني مستخدمش لغة سهلة عشان ميكونش في misconception أو أوصلك المعلومة لـ دماغك وتفكر بيها بعد كده بشكل غلط. وبرده هحاول اني مستخدمش لغة صعبة غير مفهومة هتخلي الأمور بالنسبه ليك أعقد أكتر، وده مش هدفي طبعاً.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;هنتعلم-ايه-في-الفصل-ده&#34;&gt;هنتعلم ايه في الفصل ده؟&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;هنعرف ايه هو الـ Operating system ده&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;هنتكلم عن المهام الرئيسية للـ Operating Systems&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;هنتكلم برده على ازاي الجهاز بيبدأ يشتغل أول ما بنفتحه&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;هنتعلم يعني ايه Process&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;هنفهم يعني ايه Interrupt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;هنفهم ايه الفرق ما بين الـUser Mode والـ Kernel Mode وليه هما مهمين لأي نظام تشغيل&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;وهنتكلم عن الـ System calls&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;الحاجات دي لو فهمتها كويس، كل اللي جاي هيكون سهل عليك، ان شاء الله، والمقدمة دي هتكون متقسمه لأجزاء.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spirited Away</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/cinema/anime-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/cinema/anime-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Notes on worldbuilding, creatures, and the way it treats courage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>True Detective (Season 1)</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/cinema/series-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/cinema/series-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watching notes on tone, dialogue, and visual rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the Mood for Love</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/cinema/film-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/cinema/film-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Notes on atmosphere, pacing, and the sound of corridors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tradition and Modernity: A False Dichotomy</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/tradition-and-modernity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/tradition-and-modernity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are told that we must choose. Either we embrace the new and cast off the old, or we cling to tradition and reject progress. This is a false choice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wisest cultures have always known how to hold both. They honor what has been proven by time while remaining open to genuine improvement. They distinguish between change for its own sake and change that serves human flourishing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-weight-of-inheritance&#34;&gt;The Weight of Inheritance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To inherit a tradition is to receive a gift and a responsibility. Those who came before us labored to understand the world. They made mistakes, but they also discovered truths. To dismiss their work is arrogance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Writing Clearly</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/on-writing-clearly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/on-writing-clearly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Clear writing is clear thinking made visible. When our prose is confused, it is usually because our ideas are confused. The discipline of writing forces us to discover what we actually believe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-enemy-of-clarity&#34;&gt;The Enemy of Clarity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The chief enemy of clear writing is pretension. We reach for impressive words when simple ones would serve. We construct elaborate sentences to hide the thinness of our thought. We mistake obscurity for depth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Defence of Boredom</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/defence-of-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/defence-of-boredom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have declared war on boredom. Every idle moment must be filled. We carry devices that promise infinite entertainment. We have forgotten how to wait, how to be still, how to be alone with our thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a loss greater than we know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-uses-of-emptiness&#34;&gt;The Uses of Emptiness&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Boredom is not mere absence. It is a space in which something can happen. When the mind is not occupied, it wanders. It makes unexpected connections. It surfaces thoughts long submerged.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
