<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Culture on mashally</title>
    <link>https://blackaly.github.io/tags/culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Culture on mashally</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blackaly.github.io/tags/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tradition and Modernity: A False Dichotomy</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/tradition-and-modernity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/tradition-and-modernity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are told that we must choose. Either we embrace the new and cast off the old, or we cling to tradition and reject progress. This is a false choice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wisest cultures have always known how to hold both. They honor what has been proven by time while remaining open to genuine improvement. They distinguish between change for its own sake and change that serves human flourishing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-weight-of-inheritance&#34;&gt;The Weight of Inheritance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To inherit a tradition is to receive a gift and a responsibility. Those who came before us labored to understand the world. They made mistakes, but they also discovered truths. To dismiss their work is arrogance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Defence of Boredom</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/defence-of-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/articles/defence-of-boredom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have declared war on boredom. Every idle moment must be filled. We carry devices that promise infinite entertainment. We have forgotten how to wait, how to be still, how to be alone with our thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a loss greater than we know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-uses-of-emptiness&#34;&gt;The Uses of Emptiness&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Boredom is not mere absence. It is a space in which something can happen. When the mind is not occupied, it wanders. It makes unexpected connections. It surfaces thoughts long submerged.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
