<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>All Posts on mashally</title>
    <link>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in All Posts on mashally</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blackaly.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What have I learned while working at the bank: 1</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/what-have-i-learned-while-working-at-the-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/what-have-i-learned-while-working-at-the-bank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Actually I hadn&amp;rsquo;t the change to work for the banking sector before, and when I imagine people in a classic suit sitting behind their desks in banks, I thought they were doing things I would never understand for the rest of my life. But in reality, banking is routine work as I observed until now and I cannot fully guarantee this because (there is no &lt;strong&gt;collaterals&lt;/strong&gt; for these ideas).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my current job at &lt;strong&gt;ALEXBANK&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve met a lot of people who have shared with me a lot of knowledge about a lot of concepts and different topics, and that&amp;rsquo;s fired something inside me that gave me a real passion for reading about &lt;strong&gt;money&lt;/strong&gt;, actually the current image in my main page reflects my current focus on money and gold. I still have no deep knowledge, or well-connected knowledge about how money works, but anyway, money is the only thing that keeps restoring my faith that there is no absolute justice in our world: some people suffer, while others continue to grow richer. Regardless of this philosophy, I need to share what I have learnt in banking as an Integration Engineer at &lt;strong&gt;ALEXBANK&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What happened to the people??</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/what-happend-to-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/what-happend-to-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I try to understand what’s happening to people, I’m amazed at why they do this to themselves. I don’t pretend I’m special, and yes, I make mistakes sometimes, and I have to admit I grew up around people who lived simply and within their means which made me think wisly in a lot of things around me. But what I see now is that people are living inside their minds, what is that mean? I mean people, as I see, no longer think about the consequences of what they do or what I am buying today will reflect to my expenses in the future or not, they don’t have a long-term plan for their &lt;strong&gt;financial expenses&lt;/strong&gt;. They only think about the current moment, regardless of whether what they are buying today will affect their future expenses which, in my view, is a red flag for our generation. Our generation is very easy to manipulate and control because of what people see every day on Reels and TikTok videos and you without feeling it or being aware of it, can change your attitude and way of thinking and I wouldn’t be exaggerating if I said your whole personality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>نظم التشغيل: 1</title>
      <link>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/os-ar-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackaly.github.io/posts/os-ar-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;مقدمة-عامة-تاريخ&#34;&gt;مقدمة عامة (تاريخ)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;في الشابتر ده، هنتعرف مع بعض على المفاهيم الأساسية اللي لازم تبقى فاهمها قبل ما تخش بجد في عالم الـ Operating Systems. انا هحاول في الـ tutorial دي اني مستخدمش لغة سهلة عشان ميكونش في misconception أو أوصلك المعلومة لـ دماغك وتفكر بيها بعد كده بشكل غلط. وبرده هحاول اني مستخدمش لغة صعبة غير مفهومة هتخلي الأمور بالنسبه ليك أعقد أكتر، وده مش هدفي طبعاً.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;هنتعلم-ايه-في-الفصل-ده&#34;&gt;هنتعلم ايه في الفصل ده؟&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;هنعرف ايه هو الـ Operating system ده&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;هنتكلم عن المهام الرئيسية للـ Operating Systems&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;هنتكلم برده على ازاي الجهاز بيبدأ يشتغل أول ما بنفتحه&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;هنتعلم يعني ايه Process&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;هنفهم يعني ايه Interrupt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;هنفهم ايه الفرق ما بين الـUser Mode والـ Kernel Mode وليه هما مهمين لأي نظام تشغيل&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;وهنتكلم عن الـ System calls&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;الحاجات دي لو فهمتها كويس، كل اللي جاي هيكون سهل عليك، ان شاء الله، والمقدمة دي هتكون متقسمه لأجزاء.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
